Eiji Fukuoka 5-11-19 Ogikubo Suginami-ku, Tokyo 167-0051 Home:03-5938-2604 Mobile:070-2628-1785 Email:eiji.fukuoka@gmail.com

20th Aug 2023

Dear Mr. Tateyama

I wish to apply for the position of head of sales.

As you will see in my attached resume, I have over 25 years work experience in the enterprise market. I have worked for Zoom Video Communications as a manager , Enterprise sales and supervised 5 account executives for financial, telecommunication, manufacturing and retail & service industries and then collaborated with cross function teams very closely for customer's success. I have also engaged with customer and partner's executives.

I have strong confidence to contribute to the success of team member and your company with my mind of servant leadership through my experiences.

I would be pleased to discuss application with you and I am available for an interview at your convenience. I can be contacted at the phone numbers or by email listed above.

Yours sincerely,

Eiji Fukuoka

Eiji Fukuoka

5-11-19 Ogikubo Suginami-ku Tokyo Japan TEL/FAX: +81-3-5938-2604 E-mail: eiji.fukuoka@gmail.com

Strengths and Skills

- · A team member as well as an energetic and strong leader to execute anything positively
- · Strategic solution and vision selling skills
- Build strategic and stronger trusted relationships with customer and partner's executives.
- Strong data-driven analysis/operation ,negotiation and presentation skills
- Develop sales strategy and build strong one team to achieve all targets

Senior executive with proven track record and experience in management and enterprise business Software, Hardware and Service.

Education

WASEDA University Law and Legal Studies

March, 1996

Professional Experience

2021.10 ~ Present Zoom Video Communications

Manager, Enterprise Sales

Responsible for sales lead as a head of Enterprise sales and co-working with other function leaders. Developing customer's DX as well as evolving hybrid work style.

Enterprise sales team is driving some strategic activities to expand our business such as accelerating to develop new enterprise communication platform in manufacturing companies ,working with LINE Works for their sales person of Insurance companies, developing new contact center service for

telecommunication companies with our partner and implementing our SDK into new EV car with not only communication but entertainment function for future mobility.

Focusing executive engagement to meet their expectations and corporate KPIs and hold executive round tables and effective events.

In my team, I have set KPIs and coach the team member to fill gaps with their activity data to connect with Salesforce and other dashboard in weekly cadence meeting and one on one sync meeting to motivate my team member and other leaders.

Reporting to Mr. Norihiro Shimogaki, Country manager.

- Coverage: top 300 enterprise companies (over 10,000 employees)
 Industry: Finance, Telecommunications, Manufacturing and Retail & Service
- Sales lead (the enterprise group :5 account executives)
- Sales Performance (MRR/Monthly Recurring Revenue)

FY21: new booking \$10K Achievement 265% (Account executive acting sales leader)

FY22: new booking \$335K/ Achievement 66%

FY23: Q1 new booking \$135K Achievement 139 %

2019.9 ~ 2021.9 Google Cloud

Director, Automotive Industry

Responsible for Automotive accounts as a global account director, Honda Motor and Nissan Motor in Cloud business.

(From 2020 mainly focusing Honda Motor as a key global account director)

Automotive accounts were greenfield in Google Cloud, so supported to transform their business such as infrastructure modernization & new work style under the Covid-19 and accelerating new business such as CASE and MaaS with DX while understanding their challenges, corporate priorities and KPIs deeply. Having created over \$100M pipeline (Connected Data Platform, Enterprise system Data Platform, strategic workload such as SAP and VMware, and then Google Work Space)

Building strategic relationships with C-Level executives and key stakeholders and engaging with key partners such as PwC, Accenture ,Deloitte,DXC,IBM,NTT-Group,Softbank and Cloud native companies. Collaborating with the marketing team to hold executive events and manage leads to convert quickly. Holding a cadence weekly with the account team to confirm progress of pipeline and opportunities and discuss strategy and tactics for success of the customer.

At the same time providing one Google value with the customer to lead not the cloud team but other PA units(Google Advertisement, Google Auto and Android) by organizing the cross team in greater Google.

- Coverage: Automotive (Honda Motor and Nissan Motor)
- Sales lead (the team : 3 Field sales and 2 Customer Engineers)
- Sales Performance (consumption)

FY19: new booking \$45K

FY20: new booking \$140K/ Achievement 79.2% YoY+311% Growth

2018.4 ~ 2019.8 IBM Japan, Ltd.

Director, Business Unit Executive, Country Manager of Storage System

Responsible for IBM Storage business which was not only Hardware but Software and Service. Supported all client's data-driven business and the data management by the next generation data platform, the management software and service, collaborating with other business units such as AI and Cloud and built the ecosystem across them. Maximized revenue and gross profit (P&L management) and transformed the business and the organization. Developed the activity and solution awareness through SNS and some marketing events to work with the marketing team very closely. Had two cadences weekly, one was for the team in Japan and another was with global executives to manage and develop pipeline and opportunities. Engaged in partner development to expand the sales channel. Reported to Mr. Takashi Asakai, Vice President and also Mr. Doug Balog, General Manager Storage Client Success in WW.

- Coverage: All industries (direct and indirect business)
- Management: 9 managers (sales managers, development manager, brand manager and tech managers/ total 82 people)
- Achievement:

FY18: Revenue \$86M in 2H

FY19Q1: Revenue \$39M/Achievement 122%, Profit 50%, PTI 7% YtY +14pts

FY19Q2: Revenue \$44M/ Achievement 106%, Profit 59%

2016.4 2018.4 FUKUMI Corporation.

Executive Vice President

Responsible for all sales and P&L management. Expanding the existing IoT,OEM, Life Care and BPO (3PL/Third Party Logistics and others) business and developing new business for the next generation. Had a cadence weekly to manage business pipeline, create new opportunities and coach the team how to engage with key stakeholders internally and externally

- Coverage: All business in FUKUMI Corporation
- Management : 2 General Managers and 4 Managers (25 sales people)
- Achievement and Plan: FY16 Revenue \$40M, GM \$6M

FY17 Revenue \$44M YoY+10%, GM YoY+8% Growth

2015.9 ~ 2016.3 Dassult Systems K.K.

Vice President / 3DS Business Transformation Japan

Responsible for core and direct software business which had over 20% of WW Business at the revenue point. Being a key software platform player with 3DEXPERIENCE business platform including software products such as CAD and PLM , by leveraging 3DS one team and ecosystem. Maximized revenue and managed accurate pipeline and forecast through cadence meetings weekly. Built a stronger organization with senior people and developed people skillful and motivated. Held executive events to collaborate with the marketing team.Reported to Mr. Seiji Kajiya , MD in JP and also Mr. Sylvain Laurent ,EVP global field sales in WW. Engaged with C-Level not only IT but business domain executives with high business and finance acumen.

- Coverage: All industries in Dassault Systems
- Management: 7 sales directors (50 sales people) + 1 senior Pre Sales director(60 pre sales people) + 1 Ops director (8 ops people)
- Achievement: FY15: SW Revenue \$158M/Achievement 101%, Service Signings€15.5M/126% FY16Q1:SW Revenue \$40.9M/Achievement 102%, Service Signings€6.2M/170%
- Award: FY15 No.1 Geo Award

2010.10 ~ 2015.8 Hewlett Packard Japan

2012.7 ~ 2015.8 Director & General Manager / Country Manager of HP Storage

Responsible for storage hardware and software business and its P&L management as Director and General Manager of HP Storage. Expanded storage hardware and backup & data management software business in the environment of legacy applications and new cloud or big data areas with HP converged storage. Maximized revenue and gross margin with high sales and operation management. Built a strong organization closely collaborating with other business units. Held customers and partners events successfully and created many press releases to work with the marketing team aggressively. Reported to Mr. Hiroshi Yoshida, President in HP Japan and also Mr.Phil Davis ,VP storage in HP APJ. Developed solution selling and C-Level approach with business and finance acumen.

- Coverage: All accounts(direct & indirect) and all industries
- Management: 8 direct report managers (3Sales,Marketing,Business Development,Operation, 2Pre-sales and Engineering managers) and 70 people staff
- Achievement: FY12 2H: Revenue \$116.7M/ Achievement 102%, GM \$53.3M/ 98%

FY13: Revenue \$186.7M/ Achievement 97%, GM \$92.6M/ 94%

FY14: Revenue \$150.0M/Achievement 76%, GM \$68.6M/67.2%

FY151H: Revenue \$64M / LC YoY+ 8.1%, GM \$28M /LC YoY +20.4%

2010.10 ~ 2012.6 General Manager

Mainly responsible for JT as Account General Manager who was able to handle HP all hardware, software & service, and then managing other CPG and Manufacturing accounts as a sales manager. JT is one of HP Japan's biggest accounts. Managed and led the big team globally, as the customer had 2 HQ in Japan and Switzerland. Built a closer and longer term relationship with the customer C-level executives with the view of the corporate direction. Developed my finance acumen and global management.

- Coverage: JT (globally), and part of Manufacturing and CPG companies (domestic only)
- Management: 3 direct report account managers and 140 people staff
- Achievement: FY11 order \$50.7M / Achievement 305%, GM \$22M/295%

2008.12 ~ 2010.9 SAP Japan

2010.1 ~ 2010.9 Director, Sales Department Discrete Manufacturing Industry

Responsible for ERP,BI and other software business for Manufacturing accounts. Maximized the talents of individual team members, encouraged cooperation as one team, building strong teamwork, managing fundamentals (call memo, meeting agenda report, deal status report and practice of APS, DPS and QMP) and encouraging skills up and penetrating fair assessment for the result and the process. In charge of relationship building with C-level executives of client companies and partners (Accenture, PwC, IBM, Hitachi and others)

- Industry: Automotive, Heavy metal, Machinery, Engineering, Construction and Housing productions (approximately 500 companies)
- Management: 7 direct reports and 20 members of the Discrete team
- Budget: 1.2billion yen / Sales revenue: 920million yen (as of June)/ Achievement: 102%

2008.12 ~ 2009.12. Senior Account Executive, Sales Department Manufacturing Industry

Responsible for High touch sales activities and sales training for other sales team members (APS, DPS, closing skill, solution selling, SPIN and others) Understood the customers business and process, and proposed analysis and solutions for their mid term IT plan. Also, proactively addressed to LOBs.

- Customers: Bridgestone, Yokohama Rubber, IHI, HOYA and others
- Budget: 350million yen/ Sales revenue: 570million yen / Achievement rate: 163%
 - * Received several awards including Top talent, President Award and Top performer.

2000.10. ~ 2008.11. EMC Japan

Responsible for enterprise storage hardware, backup, security & content management software. Ensured to manage fundamentals including TAS sales strategy, Solution selling, MEDDIC, SPIN selling and build my own mid to long term business plan. It was not easy to cover chemical industry customers but tried understanding customer's corporate goals and challenges and made accurate proposals to solve their issues. Able to have several meeting opportunities with C-level executives in customer companies and achieved to win trust from customers.

Succeeded in improving the accuracy of proposals and the speed. Applying Value Pyramid and other method, tried to support customers to achieve their corporate goal using IT technologies and helped analyzing and executing. Tried to understand power structure in customer companies and approached strategically those who have decision making power or influence on others. Succeeded to have several meetings with C-level executives in customers and proposed solutions which were useful to solve the customer corporate challenges.

2006.1 ~ 2008.11 Senior Account Executive, East Japan Sales Division Retail & Service District

- Customers: Seven & i Holdings, AEON Group, FamilyMart, Lawson, Mitsubishi Chemical Holdings, Mitsui Chemical, Sumitomo Chemical, Asahi Kasei, Pharmaceutical/Medicine(GSK, Sanofi-Aventis, Roche, Eisai, Chugai)
- Budget: \$5.5M / Sales Revenue: \$7M / Achievement rate 125% (2007)
- Budget: \$5.2M / Sales Revenue: \$5.2M / Achievement rate 100% (2006)
- Budget: \$8M / Sales revenue: \$8M(as of end of Nov) / Achievement rate: 100% (as of Nov)
 - **Received Top Gun award (Top sales) President award, APJ award
 - **Average achievement rate in EMC totally was over 100% as of Nov 2008

2003.1 ~ 2005.12 Account Executive ,Enterprise Business Division Telecom Sales District

- Customers: : NTT Communications, NTT Group companies (except NTT Docomo)
- Subordinates: 2 (Leaders for NTT Group)
- Budget: \$6M / Sales revenue: \$6M / Achievements rate 100% (2005)
- Budget: \$5M / Sales revenue: \$4.5M / Achievement rate 90% (2004)
- Budget: \$4.7M / Sales revenue: \$5.2M / Achievement rate: 110% (2003)

2002.1 ~ 2002.12 Senior Account Manager ,Telecom Sales District

• Customer: NTT Communications, NTTPC Communications and NTT Software (new or small)

• Budget: \$5M / Sales Revenue: \$2.2M / Achievement rate 44%(2002)

2000.10 ~ 2001.12 Senior Account Manager, Enterprise Sales Division Digital Media District

- Customers: Rakuten (New customer for EMC) and others
- Budget: \$5M / Sales revenue: \$5M / Achievement rate 100%(2001)

 Budget: \$5M(Q4:\$1.4M) / Sales revenue: -(Q4:\$1.5M) / Achievement rate 107%(2000)

1996.4 ~ 2000.10 Nissho Electronics

OEM/Channel Sales Group Leader

2000.04 ~ 2000.10 Computer business, Peripheral Group

1996. 04 ~ 2000.03 PC Product Business, Peripheral Group (1999.4~Group Leader)

Worked on customer research, relationship building and distributed the newly developed product mainly through the channel market. This became a big success and received a president award in 1999. Achieved to sell several Adaptec products to Hitachi and Oki Electric. Succeeded to build a closer relationship with Adaptec HQ.

- Sales route: OEM, Channel sales and others
- Customers: Hitachi, Mitsubishi Electronic, Oki Electric, Fujitsu, Daiwabo Information System, Softbank,
 Sofmap
- Products: U.S Adaptec SCSI card, U.S 3dfx Graphic card, U.S 3Dlabs Graphic card, and others
- Budget: 1 billion yen/Sales revenue: 800 million yen/Achievement rate: 80% (2000.4.-2000.10)

900 million yen/Sales revenue: 1.3billion yen/Achievement rate:144% (1999.4-2000.3)

900 million yen/Sales revenue: 1.2billion yen/Achievement rate: 133% (1998.4-1999.3)

600 million yen/Sales revenue: 1billion yen/Achievement rate: 166% (1997.4-1998.3)

100 million yen/Sales revenue: 200million yen/Achievement rate: 200% (1996.4-1997.3)

Skill Training

Positive Leadership Training (May, 2019)

Executive Training (July 2018)

Emotional Training (Dec 2015)

Right Management, Coaching Training (Nov, 2012)

HP Sales University, Master for General Manager (June, 2011)

IWNC Training for management team (Mar, 2010)

PMP Training for management team (Feb,2010)

TAS Training (2003,2006,2008)

Solution Selling Skill Training (Feb, 2006)